

LUCAS ASSIS RODRIGUES

iOS DEVELOPER

I am a computer engineer with experience in iOS development. I am enthusiastic about continually improving my skillset, sharing my knowledge and working with creative teams to build useful products. In my spare time I enjoy creating apps using different coding techniques and frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

Journi

Senior iOS Developer | Aug 2018 - Present

- Instructed junior developers on use of Swift programming language, creating collaborative learning environment to onboard personnel.
- Integrated 3rd-party frameworks needed for business operations. (Adyen, Facebook, Amplitude, Leanplum, Firebase)
- Implemented design patterns MVVM, Dependency Injection, MVC, Repository. (RxSwift, Combine, Swift, Objective-C)
- Worked in cross functional teams translating UI designs into features and components, and integrating RESTful APIs into the app. (UIKit, SwiftUI, Alamofire)

eWorld

Freelance Web Developer | Feb 2017 - Mar 2017

- Worked in both front-end and back-end development for the services provided by the company.
- Implemented the front-end functionalities in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Razor.
- Implemented the backend in C# using the Entity Framework to access the database.

The University of Toledo

Research Intern | May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Worked to test, bug fix and improve the functionalities of an existing structural analysis software.
- Designed and developed new data plotting features. (C++, OpenGL, MFC)
- Planned and executed measures to optimise the application memory consumption enabling more complex data analysis.

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

IT Intern | Jul 2014 - Mar 2015

- Contributed to the strategic plan for software development.
- Worked with a team to design and develop a module for the university portal website. (JSF)
- Developed backend database its respective REST API. (Hibernate, PostgreSQL)

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

Teaching Assistant | Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

- Worked with students on one-by-one interactions and groups to help with assignments, reinforce the course concepts, and improve their overall performance.
- Assisted with grading and documenting the performance of the classes.
- Assisted the professor with the following courses: Object-Oriented Programming (C++), Applied Programming (Java).

EDUCATION

Apple Developer Academy

Naples, Italy Master Class Graduated in Jun 2018

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

Itajubá, Brazil B.Sc. in Computer Engineering Graduated in Dec 2016

PROJECTS

- Designed and developed the <u>website</u> for the Vienna Science Fair an event held by UN/IAEA employees. (ReactJS, Vapor Codes, Heroku)
- Developed and published several personal iOS apps to the <u>App Store</u>. (SwiftUI, UIKit, Git, Sketch, Xcode, CoreData)